Overview of the Paul Navarro Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Paul Navarro collection
1965-2006
2007C44
Navarro, Paul, collector
3 manscript boxes (1.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Sound recordings of interviews and printed matter, relating to the Partido Comunista del Perú (Patria Roja or Red Nation). Includes pamphlets, serial issues and programmatic statements by the party; some material relating to other Maoist parties in Peru; and a study by Paul Navarro, "Maoism in the Andes: A Concise History of the Partido Comunista del Perú--Patria Roja, 1960-1992."
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2007.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Sound recordings of interviews and printed matter, relating to the Partido Comunista del Perú (Patria Roja or Red Nation). Includes pamphlets, serial issues and programmatic statements by the party; some material relating to other Maoist parties in Peru; and a study by Paul Navarro, "Maoism in the Andes: A Concise History of the Partido Comunista del Perú--Patria Roja, 1960-1992."
Navarro assembled the collection for his senior honors thesis at Stanford. Through family connections in the party he acquired a unique and invaluable group of interviews and party documents. His excellent 150-page study of the Red Nation, and political/military conflict in Peru generally, was written under the direction of Hoover fellow Herbert Klein.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Partido Comunista del Perú (Patria Roja); Communism--Peru.; Phonotapes.
Partial Collection Contents
- Sound recordings, 2005
  - Sound recording of Zety interview, 2005 July 13
    Use copy reference number: 2007c44_a_0000560
  - Sound recording of Miguel interview, 2005 July 11
    Use copy reference number: 2007c44_a_0000561
  - Sound recording of Ching interview, undated
    Use copy reference number: 2007c44_a_0000562
  - Sound recording, Lvdo, 2005 August 30
    Use copy reference number: 2007c44_a_0000563
  - Sound recording of Kobi interview, 2005 August 29
    Use copy reference number: 2007c44_a_0000564
  - Sound recording of Mosquera interview, October 9
    Use copy reference number: 2007c44_a_0000566
  - Sound recording of Saleveri interview, undated
    Use copy reference number: 2007c44_a_0000567
  - Sound recording of Alberto Moreno interview, undated
    Use copy reference number: 2007c44_a_0000568
  - Sound recording of Santander interview, undated
    Use copy reference number: 2007c44_a_0000569
  - Sound recording of Rolando interview, undated
    Use copy reference number: 2007c44_a_0000574
  - Sound recording of Raul Gonzales interview, undated
    Use copy reference number: 2007c44_a_0000575
- Rest of collection not yet described